happythreads.ie 2013-04-08

# Introduction and General Terms

[Home](http://www.happythreads.ie/ "Introduction to MODx") » Introduction and General Terms

Telescopic Healthcare is committed to protecting you and your family's personal information when you are using Telescopic Healthcare services. We want our services to be safe and enjoyable environments for our audience. This Privacy Policy relates to our use of any personal information you provide to us through the happythreads.ie website. 

In order to provide you with the full range of Telescopic Healthcare services, we are sometimes required to collect information about you. 

This privacy policy explains the following: 

  * what information Telescopic Healthcare may collect about you; 
  * how Telescopic Healthcare will use information we collect about you; 
  * when Telescopic Healthcare may use your details to contact you; 
  * whether Telescopic Healthcare will disclose your details to anyone else; 
  * your choices regarding the personal information you have provided to us; 
  * the use of cookies on the Telescopic Healthcare website and how you can reject these cookies. 

As set out above, Telescopic Healthcare is committed to safeguarding your personal information. Whenever you provide such information, we are legally obliged to use your information in line with all laws concerning the protection of personal information, including the Data Protection Act 1998 (these laws are referred to collectively in this Privacy Policy as the "data protection laws"). 

The website may contain hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These third party websites have their own privacy policies, including cookies, and we urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information you submit or are collected by cookies whilst visiting these websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk. 

## What information will Telescopic Healthcare collect about me? 

When you sign up to participate in or receive a service from Telescopic Healthcare such as newsletters or articles we may ask for personal information about you. This can consist of information such as your name, e-mail address, or postal address. By entering your details in the fields requested, you enable Telescopic Healthcare to provide you with the services you select. 

## How will Telescopic Healthcare use the information they collect about me? 

Telescopic Healthcare will use your personal information for a number of purposes including the following: 

  * for "service administration purposes", which means that Telescopic Healthcare may contact you for reasons related to the service you have signed up for, as set out below (e.g. to provide you with password reminders or to notify you that a particular service has been suspended for maintenance); 
  * IP addresses may be used to identify the location of users, the number of visits from different countries and also to block disruptive use. 

Where Telescopic Healthcare proposes using your personal information for any other uses we will ensure that we notify you first. You will also be given the opportunity to withhold or withdraw your consent for your use other than as listed above. 

## When will Telescopic Healthcare contact me? 

Telescopic Healthcare may contact you: 

  * in relation to the functioning of any service you have signed up for in order to ensure that Telescopic Healthcare can deliver the services to you; 
  * to invite you to participate in surveys about Telescopic Healthcare services (participation is always voluntary); and 
  * for marketing purposes where you have not asked to be excluded from this. 

## Will I be contacted for marketing purposes? 

Telescopic Healthcare won't contact you for marketing purposes, or promote new services to you if you ask not to be contacted for these purposes. 

## Will Telescopic Healthcare share my personal information with anyone else? 

We will keep your information confidential and we will only use your information within Telescopic Healthcare. 

## What if I am a user aged 16 or under? 

If you are aged 16 or under, please get your parent/guardian's permission beforehand whenever you provide personal information to the Telescopic Healthcare website. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information. 

## How long will Telescopic Healthcare keep my personal information? 

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant service. 

## Can I find out what personal information Telescopic Healthcare holds about me? 

Under the Data Protection Act you have the right to request a copy of the personal information Telescopic Healthcare holds about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. We will use reasonable efforts to supply, correct or delete personal information about you on our files. 

Please contact [daniel@happythreads.ie ](mailto:capp@cappeu.org) if you have any questions relating to data protection. 

## Changes to Telescopic Healthcare's Privacy Policy 

This privacy policy may be updated from time to time so you may wish to check it each time you submit personal information the Telescopic Healthcare website. 

## Cookies Policy - Information Telescopic Healthcare collects from you 

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes a unique identifier that is sent to your computer or mobile phone (referred to here as a "device") browser from a website's computer and is stored on your device's hard drive. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites. Many sites do this whenever a user visits their website in order to track online traffic flows. 

Cookies record information about your online preferences and can allow us to tailor the website to your interests. Users have the opportunity to set their devices to accept all cookies, to notify them when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. The last of these means that certain personalised services cannot then be provided to that user and accordingly you may not be able to take full advantage of all of the happythreads.ie features. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. 

During the course of any visit to happythreads.ie the pages you see, along with a cookie, are downloaded to your device. Many websites do this, because cookies enable website publishers to do useful things like find out whether the device (and probably its user) has visited the website before. This is done on a repeat visit by checking to see, and finding, the cookie left there on the last visit. Information supplied by cookies can help us to analyse the profile of our visitors and help us to provide you with a better user experience. 

## Contacting the Telescopic Healthcare about this Privacy Policy 

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy please contact [daniel@happythreads.ie ](mailto:contactcapp@cappeu.org)
